<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tim Lortz</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tim Lortz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Performance of Autofitting Time Series Models</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/comparing-performance-of-autofitting-time-series-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/comparing-performance-of-autofitting-time-series-models/</guid>
      <description>Overview In several recent client and personal projects, I’ve found a need to quickly create robust real-time anomaly detection for time series data. In the typical use case, the goal is to fit a model to as much historical data as possible, then use that model to predict future time series values. When the predictions are compared against new observed data, if the observed data appears to fall too far away from the predicted values, it is flagged for follow-on analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Your Own Netflow</title>
      <link>/2018/09/03/make-your-own-netflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/03/make-your-own-netflow/</guid>
      <description>What is Netflow, and Why Would I Want It? Netflow is a network traffic summary mechanism originally developed by Cisco for the purpose of monitoring network traffic loads for billing. In its simplest form, Netflow summarizes all of the &amp;ldquo;flows&amp;rdquo; - roughly the equivalent of a TCP/IP session - seen at a router and summarizes them by source and destination address and port and the layer 3 or 4 protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Apache Spark 2.3 with Jupyter on Mac OSX</title>
      <link>/2018/08/13/spark-jupyter-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/13/spark-jupyter-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Through promotional materials from Databricks earlier this year, I had heard about the upcoming Spark 2.3 release. I sat in a demo and was really excited to try out new features like Continuous Processing and MLlib in Structured Streaming. But my customer work is all done in Spark 2.2 at the moment, and none of my side projects really required distributed processing at scale. Then I went to Spark Summit earlier this summer, and after seeing more Spark 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>